Ren d'Harnoncourt Papers
The Museum of Modern Art, Publisher
- Series VII.: Correspondence with outside organizations, 1940s-1968
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1960-61; Minutes of Censorship Committee meetings. (Folder VII.7)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1956-57; Correspondence, minutes of Censorship Panel meetings. (Folder VII.8)
  - American Council on Education, 1959-62; Correspondence, minutes of meetings of Committee on Leaders and Specialists of which RDH was a member. (Folder VII.9)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1956-57; Report on a program for a national organization devoted to the advancement of the humanistic studies (American Council of Learned Societies). (Folder VII.10)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1950-51; Correspondence; report on a conference on Living in Industrial Civilization, which was attended by RDH. (Folder VII.11)
  - American Craftsmens Council, 1967-68; Minutes of meetings of the board of trustees of the American Craftsmens Council, and some correspondence related to the meetings. (Folder VII.12)
  - American Craftsmens Council, 1967-68; Minutes of meetings of the board of trustees of the American Craftsmens Council, and some correspondence related to the meetings. (Folder VII.13)
  - American Craftsmens Council, 1965-66; Minutes of meetings of the board of trustees of the American Craftsmens Council, and some correspondence related to the meetings. (Folder VII.14)
  - American Craftsmens Council, 1965-66; Minutes of meetings of the board of trustees of the American Craftsmens Council, and some correspondence related to the meetings. (Folder VII.15)
  - American Craftsmens Council, 1960-64; Minutes of meetings of the board of trustees of the American Craftsmens Council, and some correspondence related to the meetings. Program and other material on the First World Congress of Craftsmen, sponsored by the Council and held in New York (6/8 - 6/19/64). (Folder VII.16)
  - American Craftsmens Council, 1960-64; Minutes of meetings of the board of trustees of the American Craftsmens Council, and some correspondence related to the meetings. (Folder VII.17)
  - American Craftsmens Council, 1958-59; Minutes of meetings of the board of trustees of the American Craftsmens Council, and some correspondence related to the meetings. (Folder VII.18)
  - American Craftsmens Council, 1956-57; Minutes of meetings of the board of trustees of the American Craftsmens Council, and some correspondence related to the meetings. (Folder VII.19)
  - American Craftsmens Council, 1954-55; Minutes of meetings of the board of trustees of the American Craftsmens Council, and some correspondence related to the meetings. Annual Report 1955, in which it is noted that the Councils name has been changed from American Craftsmens Educational Council to American Craftsmens Council. (Folder VII.20)
  - American Craftsmens Educational Council, 1952-53; Correspondence and minutes of trustees meetings. (Folder VII.21)
  - American Craftsmens Educational Council, 1946-51; Correspondence, reports, and minutes of trustees meetings. (Folder VII.22)
  - American Craftsmens Educational Council, 1946-51; Correspondence, reports, and minutes of trustees meetings. (Folder VII.23)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1965-66; Minutes of trustees meetings; correspondence. (Folder VII.24)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1960-64; Minutes of trustees meetings; correspondence. (Folder VII.25)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1960-64; Minutes of trustees meetings, correspondence. (Folder VII.26)
  - American Federation of Arts 1963 Convention, 1962-63; Correspondence about AFA convention held in Fort Worth, Texas (5/22 - 5/24/63). Address by RDH at the convention on The Art Museums Role in International Cultural Exchange (5/23/63). Newspaper clipping announcing that RDH will be one of the featured speakers at the convention (5/16/63). (Folder VII.27)
  - American Federation of Arts 50th Anniversary - 1959, 1958-59; Correspondence about the awards made as part of the AFAs 50th Anniversary celebration. Copy of the AFA newsletter containing the citations read at the luncheon in Washington, D.C., 4/24/59, to the four award winners, one of whom was Alfred Hamilton Barr, Jr. (Folder VII.28)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1958-59; Correspondence. A report of the Board of Trustees, New Dimensions for the American Federation of Arts, from John G. Holmes Associates, Inc. (5/16/58). (Folder VII.29)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1958-59; Minutes of meetings of the Board of Trustees and the Executive Committee. Some correspondence. (Folder VII.30)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1956-57; Minutes of meetings, correspondence, material on AFA 1957 Convention. (Folder VII.31)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1954-55; Minutes of meetings, correspondence. (Folder VII.32)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1954-55; Minutes of meetings, correspondence. (Folder VII.33)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1950-51; Correspondence, minutes of trustees meetings. (Folder VII.34)
  - American Federation of Arts Magazine of Art, 1950-51; Correspondence, reports, minutes of meetings of editorial board of the Magazine of Art. (Folder VII.35)
  - American Studies Association, 1958-59; Membership letter and note that dues have been sent. (Folder VII.36)
  - University of the Andes Foundation, 1963-64; Correspondence, minutes of meetings of members and directors. RDH submitted his resignation as a director of the foundation (11/19/63). (Folder VII.37)
  - University of the Andes Foundation, 1958-59; Correspondence; statement about University of the Andes; list of members of the board of directors. 1 TLS NAR - RDH (1/13/58) inviting him to become a director of the newly-formed foundation. 2 TLS NAR - RDH (1/31/58 and 4/15/58) thanking him for agreeing to serve on the board and for his support with the program. (Folder VII.38)
  - Artist Tenants Association, 1964; Correspondence, notices about the association, minutes of meeting of the association with art organizations, 5/21/64. (Folder VII.39)
  - Artists Equity Association, 1949-51; Correspondence. Resolutions passed at the Third Woodstock Art Conference, 9/1- 9/2/50. (Folder VII.40)
  - Association of Art Museum Directors, 1965-67; Minutes of the annual meetings of AAMD, correspondence. (Folder VII.41)
  - Association of Art Museum Directors, 1960-61; Minutes of meetings, correspondence. (Folder VII.42)
  - Association of Art Museum Directors, 1960-62; Minutes of meetings, correspondence. (Folder VII.43)
  - Association of Art Museum Directors, 1958-59; Minutes of meetings, correspondence. (Folder VII.44)
  - Association of Art Museum Directors, 1955-57; Reports on the 37th and 39th sessions of AAMD. (Folder VII.45)
  - Association of Art Museum Directors, 1949-51; Reports on the 31st and 32nd sessions of AAMD. (Folder VII.46)
  - The Brearley School, 1960-67; Correspondence, minutes of trustees meetings. RDHs resignation from the board of trustees of the Brearley School, May 1964. (Folder VII.47)
  - The Brearley School, 1958-59; Correspondence, minutes of trustees meetings. (Folder VII.48)
  - The Brearley School, 1955-57; Minutes of trustees meetings, financial statements. (Folder VII.49)
  - The Brearley School, 1952-55; Correspondence, minutes of trustees meetings. (Folder VII.50)
  - Amon Carter Museum of Western Art, 1965-68; RDH correspondence with Mitchell Wilder, director of the Amon Carter Museum, newspaper clippings. (Folder VII.51)
  - Amon Carter Museum of Western Art, 1965-67; Agendas for trustees meetings. (Folder VII.52)
  - Amon Carter Museum of Western Art, 1965-68; Proposed budgets, financial statement. (Folder VII.53)
  - Amon Carter Museum of Western Art, 1960-64; RDH correspondence with Mitchell Wilder, director of the Amon Carter Museum, and with Mrs. J. Lee Johnson III (Ruth), daughter of Amon Carter, and chairman of the board of the Museum. Newspaper clippings. (Folder VII.54)
  - Amon Carter Museum of Western Art, 1961-64; Agendas and minutes of trustees meetings. (Folder VII.55)
  - Center for Inter-American Relations, 1967-68; Correspondence. Newspaper clippings about the opening of the Center at 680 Park Avenue, New York on September 18, 1967. List of board of directors. 1TLS Vice President Hubert H. Humphrey - RDH (9/22/67) enclosing a copy of the speech he made at the gala opening of the Center for Inter-American Relations. Copy of RDH letter thanking the vice president (10/4/67). (Folder VII.56)
  - Center for Inter-American Relations, 1967-68; General statement of the purpose and program of the Center, its history, structure, and by-laws, minutes of meetings, material on programs to be organized by the Center, and on its library. (Folder VII.57)
  - Center for Inter-American Relations, 1966; Correspondence and plans for the Center. Copies of the original architectural plans by McKim, Mead and White for the building at 680 Park Avenue. (Folder VII.58)
  - Century Club, 1963-68; Correspondence about prospective members of the Century Association. (Folder VII.59)
  - Century Club, 1960-64; Correspondence. (Folder VII.60)
  - Century Club, 1958-59; Correspondence. (Folder VII.61)
  - Century Club, 1955-57; Correspondence, minutes of meetings of the Committee on Exhibitions of the Century Association. (Folder VII.62)
  - Century Club, 1954-55; Correspondence, minutes of meetings of the Committee on Exhibitions of the Century Association. (Folder VII.63)
  - Century Club, 1952-53; Correspondence, minutes of meetings of the Committee on Exhibitions of the Century Association. (Folder VII.64)
  - Century Club, 1947-51; Correspondence, some of it about exhibitions at the Century Club organized by RDH, minutes of meetings of the Committee on Exhibitions of the Century Association. 1 TLS Conger Goodyear - RDH (9/29/50) thanking him for the catalog of the Baker collection. The catalog was for an exhibition of works from the collection of Walter Cummings Baker called Greek, Etruscan, and Roman Antiquities. Arranged by RDH, the exhibition was held at the Century Club 5/17-9/25/50. (Folder VII.65)
  - Century Club, 1947-51; Correspondence, some of it about exhibitions at the Century Club organized by RDH, minutes of meetings of the Committee on Exhibitions of the Century Association. (Folder VII.66)
  - Century 21 Exposition - Seattle, 1958-62; Correspondence, minutes of meeting of subcommittee on the People Division of the Century 21 Exposition (1/17/59), brochure on the Exposition. (Folder VII.67)
  - College Art Association, 1960-64; Correspondence, notices about meetings. (Folder VII.68)
  - College Art Association, 1958-59; Correspondence, notices about meetings. (Folder VII.69)
  - College Art Association, 1955-57; Correspondence, notices about meetings. (Folder VII.70)
  - Columbia University - Advisory Council of the Department of Art History and Archaeology, 1965-68; Correspondence, minutes of advisory council meetings, reports. (Folder VII.71)
  - Columbia University - Advisory Council of the Department of Art History and Archaeology, 1960-64; Correspondence, minutes of advisory council meetings, reports. (Folder VII.72)
  - Columbia University - Advisory Council of the Department of Art History and Archaeology, 1960-64; Correspondence, minutes of advisory council meetings, reports. (Folder VII.73)
  - Columbia University - Art Center, 1959; Correspondence and brochure on a proposed art center. (Folder VII.74)
  - Columbia University - Art Scholarship Benefit, 1959; Correspondence and other material on a benefit exhibition for the scholarship fund of the Department of Fine Arts and Archaeology to be held at the Knoedler Gallery 10/13-11/8/59. (Folder VII.75)
  - Cooper Union Museum, 1963; Correspondence about the proposed dispersal of the collection of the Cooper Union Museum. (Folder VII.76)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1952-64; Correspondence, notices about meetings. Correspondence between RDH and David Rockefeller about RDHs election as a member of the Council, 12/52. (Folder VII.77)
  - Committee to Rescue Italian Art, 1966-70; Announcement and other material about two fellowships to be awarded by CRIA, the Committee to Rescue Italian Art founded after the floods in Florence and Venice in November 1966. (Folder VII.78)
  - Dartmouth College - Hopkins Center, Crafts Advisory Group, 1962-65; Correspondence and other material on the Crafts Advisory Group, of which RDH was a member. (Folder VII.79)
  - Drawing Society, Inc., 1960-63; Correspondence. 1 TLS Lloyd Goodrich - RDH (11/18/60) outlining the purposes of the Drawing Society, and asking RDH to serve as a National Committee member. Copy letter RDH - Lloyd Goodrich (12/19/60) saying he greatly appreciates the invitation and will be delighted to serve. (Folder VII.80)
  - Economic Cooperation Administration, Washington, 1950-51; Correspondence between RDH, Edgar Kaufmann, Jr., and Robert R. Mullen Director, Office of Information, and Donald W. Dresden, Chief, Special Media Branch, Economic Cooperation Administration about an exhibition showing American design in home furnishings and related fields to be shown in the principal cities of Europe. (Folder VII.81)
  - Empire State Music Festival, Inc., 1959-63; Correspondence between RDH and Frank Forest, president, Empire State Music Festival. Newspaper clippings and other material on the festival. (Folder VII.82)
  - Everson Museum, Syracuse, N.Y., 1967; 1 TLS Rodman Rockefeller - RDH (11/29/67) enclosing I.M. Pei drawings of the Everson Museum. (Folder VII.83)
  - Finch College Museum of Art, 1966; Catalogs of exhibitions sent in relation to an application for employment at MoMA. (Folder VII.84)
  - Ford Foundation, 1950-52; Correspondence relating to attempt to get financial help from the Ford Foundation for the exhibition,The Family of Man, and other exhibitions. Ford Foundation annual reports. Copy letter NAR - Henry Ford, II (11/16/50) describing the achievements of MoMA, and asking whether the Ford Foundation would join with it as co-sponsor of an expanded program of traveling exhibitions. (Folder VII.85)
  - France-America Society, 1959-65; Correspondence. Annual booklets for members. (Folder VII.86)
  - Committee on Government and Art, 1955-56; Correspondence, copies of Bills, copies of the Congressional Record. (Folder VII.87)
  - Committee on Government and Art, 1955-56; Correspondence, copies of Bills, copies of the Congressional Record. (Folder VII.88)
  - Committee on Government and Art, 1955-56; Correspondence, copies of Bills, copies of the Congressional Record. (Folder VII.89)
  - Committee on Government and Art, 1955-56; Correspondence, copies of Bills, copies of the Congressional Record. (Folder VII.90)
  - Committee on Government and Art, 1954-55; Correspondence, copies of Bills, copies of the Congressional Record, reports. (Folder VII.91)
  - Committee on Government and Art, 1954-55; Correspondence, etc. (Folder VII.92)
  - Committee on Government and Art, 1954-55; Correspondence, etc. (Folder VII.93)
  - Committee on Government and Art, 1951-52; Correspondence, report on proposed UNESCO program. (Folder VII.94)
  - Glen Canyon Dam Project - Colorado River, Arizona, 1965-66; RDH correspondence with John DeWitt and others at the Bureau of Reclamation, U.S. Department of the Interior, about selecting an Indian sculptor to create a work suitable for space near the dam. Photographs of the dam. (Folder VII.95)
  - Grand Coulee Dam Project - Columbia River, Washington, 1966-68; RDH correspondence with John DeWitt and others at the Bureau of Reclamation, U.S. Department of the Interior, about the Grand Coulee Dam Powerplant project. Correspondence about RDHs agreeing to serve again on the Bureau of Reclamations board of artistic consultants. Press release announcing that Marcel Breuer is to provide architectural design for Grand Coulee Powerplant (2/18/68). (Folder VII.96)
  - Glen Canyon Dam and Grand Coulee Dam Projects, 1967-68; Photographs, preliminary design studies. (Folder VII.97)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1962-66; RDH references for applicants seeking Guggenheim Fellowships. (Folder VII.98)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1952-59; RDH references for applicants seeking Guggenheim Fellowships. (Folder VII.99)
  - Hanover Institute, 1946-48; Correspondence with the Hanover Institute, which was conducting research on the nature of perception. Hanover Institute publications. Copy letter with attached statement to Adelbert Ames, researcher at the Hanover Institute, from John Dewey (12/5/46). (Folder VII.100)
  - International Council of Museums - ICOM, 1948-51; Correspondence, reports. Report on the proceedings of the meeting of the committee on museum techniques, Stockholm (5/8-13/50). (Folder VII.101)
  - International Council of Museums - ICOM, 1948-51; Correspondence, reports. (Folder VII.102)
  - International Council of Museums - ICOM, 1956; Report on 4th general conference of ICOM (7/2 - 7/9/56) (In French). (Folder VII.103)
  - Association on American Indian Affairs, 1967-68; Correspondence, minutes of meetings. (Folder VII.104)
  - Association on American Indian Affairs, 1965-66; Correspondence, minutes of meetings. (Folder VII.105)
  - Association on American Indian Affairs, 1960-64; Correspondence, minutes of meetings. (Folder VII.106)
  - Association on American Indian Affairs, 1960-64; Correspondence, minutes of meetings. (Folder VII.107)
  - Association on American Indian Affairs, 1958-59; Correspondence, minutes of meetings. (Folder VII.108)
  - Association on American Indian Affairs, 1957; Correspondence, minutes of meetings. (Folder VII.109)
  - Association on American Indian Affairs, 1956; Correspondence, minutes of meetings. (Folder VII.110)
  - Association on American Indian Affairs, 1956; Correspondence, minutes of meetings. (Folder VII.111)
  - Association on American Indian Affairs, 1955; Correspondence, minutes of meetings. (Folder VII.112)
  - Association on American Indian Affairs, 1954-55; Correspondence, minutes of meetings. (Folder VII.113)
  - Association on American Indian Affairs, 1950-51; Correspondence, minutes of meetings. (Folder VII.114)
  - Association on American Indian Affairs, 1940s; Correspondence, minutes of meetings. (Folder VII.115)
  - Center for Arts of Indian America, 1965-68; Correspondence, newspaper clippings. 1 TLS Stewart L. Udall, Secretary of the Interior - RDH (12/29/65) asking him to serve on the Selections Committee for an exhibition of American Indian art to be shown at the 1966 Edinburgh Festival. 1 TLS Lee Udall (Mrs. Stewart L. Udall) - RDH (5/10/66) asking him to serve as a member of the Board of the Center for Arts of Indian America. Minutes of first meeting of Board of Directors of the Center (2/1/67). Progress Report (6/11/68). (Folder VII.116)
  - Indian Arts and Crafts Board, 1967-68; Correspondence, minutes of meetings, material on exhibitions. (Folder VII.117)
  - Indian Arts and Crafts Board, 1965-66; Correspondence, minutes of meetings, material on exhibitions. (Folder VII.118)
  - Indian Arts and Crafts Board, 1965-66; Correspondence, minutes of meetings, material on exhibitions. (Folder VII.119)
  - Indian Arts and Crafts Board, 1965-66; Correspondence, minutes of meetings, material on exhibitions. 1 TLS Stewart L. Udall, Secretary of the Interior - RDH (2/15/66) telling him that the Indian Bureau and the Indian Arts and Crafts Board are going to be reorganized. 1 copy letter RDH - Stewart L. Udall (3/22/66) acknowledging his letter. 1 ALS Stewart L. Udall - RDH (3/31/66) thanking him for his response. (Folder VII.120)
  - Indian Arts and Crafts Board, 1963-64; Correspondence, material on exhibitions. 1 TLS Senator Ernest Gruening - RDH (7/6/64) saying that he hopes the Indian Arts and Crafts Board will continue its support of the excellent work being done by Alaska Indian Arts, Inc. under the direction of Carl W. Heinmiller. (Folder VII.121)
  - Indian Arts and Crafts Board, 1963-64; Correspondence, material on exhibitions. (Folder VII.122)
  - Indian Arts and Crafts Board, 1960-62; Correspondence. (Folder VII.123)
  - Indian Arts and Crafts Board, 1961-62; Reports. (Folder VII.124)
  - Indian Arts and Crafts Board, 1960-62; Correspondence. (Folder VII.125)
  - Indian Arts and Crafts Board, 1960; Correspondence, reports, material on exhibitions. (Folder VII.126)
  - Indian Arts and Crafts Board, 1958-59; Correspondence. Report by RDH as Chairman of the Indian Arts and Crafts Board on American Indian Arts and Crafts at Mid-Century. (Folder VII.127)
  - Indian Arts and Crafts Board, 1958; Correspondence. Remarks made by RDH at the annual Inter-tribal Indian Ceremonial in Gallup, New Mexico, 8/15/58. (Folder VII.128)
  - Indian Arts and Crafts Board, 1955-57; Correspondence, minutes of meetings, reports. (Folder VII.129)
  - Indian Arts and Crafts Board, 1955-57; Correspondence, minutes of meetings, reports. (Folder VII.130)
  - Indian Arts and Crafts Board, 1954-55; Correspondence, reports. (Folder VII.131)
  - Indian Arts and Crafts Board, 1953-54; Correspondence, reports. (Folder VII.132)
  - Indian Arts and Crafts Board, 1950-52; Correspondence. (Folder VII.133)
  - Indian Arts and Crafts Board, 195051; Correspondence, minutes of meetings, reports. (Folder VII.134)
  - Indian Arts and Crafts Board, 1947-48; Correspondence. (Folder VII.135)
  - Indian Arts and Crafts Board - Alaska, 1945-50; Correspondence, reports. (Folder VII.136)
  - Indian Arts and Crafts Board, 1943; Collection of reports and documents concerning the activities of the Indian Arts and Crafts Board, 1936-43. Several of the reports are by RDH who was General Manager of the Indian Arts and Crafts Board in 1943. (Folder VII.137)
  - Institute of Ethnic Affairs, 1945-50; Correspondence, minutes of meetings, news letters. (Folder VII.138)
  - Institute of International Education, 1960-68; Correspondence, reports. (Folder VII.139)
  - Institute of International Education, 1958-59; Correspondence. Program of conference on Inter-American Exchange of Persons, co-sponsored by the Institute of International Education, Puerto Rico, 10/14 -10/18/58, and report on one symposium which was chaired by RDH. (Folder VII.140)
  - Institute of International Education, 1955-57; Correspondence, reports. Copy of talk given by JTS as a panel member at the Institute of International Education Conference on Exchanges in the Arts, 10/4-10/5/56. (Folder VII.141)
  - Institute of International Education, 1950-52; Correspondence, letters of recommendation, reports on Guggenheim, Fulbright, and other awards available. (Folder VII.142)
  - Institute of Inter-American Affairs, 1953; Correspondence and reports on RDHs trip to several countries in South America in 1953 to evaluate the state of crafts production (manual industry). (Folder VII.143)
  - Laboratory of Anthropology, 1944-47; Correspondence, minutes of meetings, newsletters. (Folder VII.144)
  - LaGuardia Memorial, 1963-64; Correspondence. (Folder VII.145)
  - Lincoln Center, 1965-66; Correspondence. (Folder VII.146)
  - Lincoln Center, 1960-64; Correspondence and other material on the planning and construction of Lincoln Center. 1 TLS William Schuman, President, Lincoln Center - RDH (10/11/62) thanking him for his letter of congratulation on the opening of the Center. Program of New York Philharmonic Inaugural Concert in Philharmonic Hall, 9/23/62. Program of New York State Theater Inaugural Performances, April 1964. (Folder VII.147)
  - Lincoln Center, 1960-64; Correspondence and other material on the planning and construction of Lincoln Center. (Folder VII.148)